Friend: Is there a New Year’s Eve that you always remember?
Anna: Yes, it was when I was seventeen years old, so quite a long time ago.
But it’s definitely my most memorable one.
Friend: Where were you?
Anna: Well, a friend invited me to Edinburgh for New Year’s Eve.
I was still at school, but my friend, she was older than me, she was nineteen, and she was at university in Edinburgh.
My parents didn’t want me to go, but in the end, they said OK.
I was incredibly excited because ‘Hogmanay’, that’s what they call New Year’s Eve in Scotland, is the biggest celebration in,
in Europe, I think, with thousands of people in the streets.
Friend: So what happened?
Anna: We decided to go and watch the fireworks from the top of Calton Hill, that’s a high point in the city where there’s a good view.
My friend had a Norwegian flatmate, and she also had some friends staying, some Norwegian girls from Oslo.
We all had a dinner first in their flat and then started walking to Calton Hill.
It was cold, but not snowing or raining, which was good.
The Norwegian girls bought some small fireworks, and started lighting them in the street,
they said that’s typical in Norway, that people set off fireworks in the street, and suddenly one firework hit me in the face.
Friend: How awful!
Anna: Yes, it was horrible, incredibly painful and for a few minutes, I couldn’t see at all.
Friend: What did you do?
Anna: Well, luckily there were ambulances driving round the city because actually quite a lot of people get injured in Edinburgh on New Year’s Eve,
and my friends quickly found one and they went with me to hospital.
The doctors looked at me, and it wasn’t too serious, but they put a big bandage on my face, and over one eye.
Friend: So where were you at midnight?
Anna: Well, we were still at the hospital, so we never celebrated Hogmanay properly.
I didn’t phone my parents, because there was nothing they could do,
but when I went home the next day and they saw my face, they were really shocked and angry because somehow they thought it was my fault!
But some weeks later my friends came down to London and we had a fantastic party to make up for missing New Year’s Eve.